Planned Parenthood League of Massachusetts, 1859-2002 (bulk 1916-1960)
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES X. MICROFILM
  - Birth control League of Massachusetts
    - Apr 1936-Jun 1939 (Reel 2)
      - Raids on clinics in Massachusetts 1937 (Reel 2)
    - Raids and trials 1937-38 (Reel 2)
    - Mother's Health Center, Apr 1937-Feb 1938
      - Opening of Mother's Health Center (Reel 2)
      - General Massachusetts subjects including raids (Reel 2)
    - Mother's Health CouncilDec 1938-Apr 1941 (Reel 2)
      - General re.: Massachusetts and Connecticut (Reel 2)
      - Holyoke speech by Margaret Sanger on opening of drive for initiative petition (Reel 2)
      - Other speeches in Massachusetts by Sanger (Reel 2)
      - Drive for signatures for initiative petition to give Massachusetts physicians the right to prescribe contraceptives to married persons (Reel 2)
  - Massachusetts Mother's Health Council
    - General subjects - polls, marriage, birth controlFeb 1919-Mar 1941 (Reel 3)
    - Apr 1941-Dec 1942 Allied clippings - general articles on birth rate, birth control, marriage (Reel 3)
    - Oct 1942-Dec 1946 (Reel 3)
      - Articles on "birth control" referendum, Question No. 1 on the ballot, ads taken out pro and con (Reel 3)
      - Articles on rejection of the bill (Reel 3)
      - General articles (Reel 3)
      - Clergy and birth control (Reel 3)
    - Apr 1941-Oct 1942 (Reel 3)
      - Connecticut birth control (Reel 3)
      - Birth control Bill defeated in MassachusettsJune 1941 (Reel 3)
      - 1941 ballot and birth control (Reel 3)
  - American Birth Control League 1930-Jan 1931 companionate marriages, Judge Ben B. Lindsey (Reel 4)
    - 1931-Jan 1932 (Reel 4)
      - Lambeth Conference of Anglican bishops (Reel 4)
      - Pope Pius XI encyclical on marriage and birth control (Reel 4)
      - Gillett bill in U.S. senate. Margaret Sanger testifies (Reel 4)
      - Massachusetts birth control pill (Reel 4)
      - Churches and birth control (Reel 4)
      - State leagues (Reel 4)
      - Margaret Sanger's "birth moratorium" (Reel 4)
    - 1931-32 General articles on birth control (Reel 4)
    - Jan 1932-Jan 1933 (Reel 4)
      - State affiliated leagues (Reel 4)
      - New York city clippings (Reel 4)
      - Miscellaneous (Reel 4)
      - Visit of Baroness Ishimoto (Reel 4)
      - National Legislation (Reel 4)
    - 1933-1934Meetings (Reel 4)
    - 1934 (Reel 4)
      - Pierce Bill, U.S. House of Representatives, to legalize dissemination of birth control information by physicians and clinics (Reel 4)
      - Testimony before House Judiciary Committee: Father Charles Coughlin, Mr. Thomas Hepburn and Margaret Sanger (Reel 4)
      - Birth control, general articles pro and con (Reel 4)
      - Sterilization, Germany and Britain (Reel 4)
      - Birth Control conferences and meetings (Reel 4)
    - Oct 1934-May 1935 (Reel 4)
      - GeneralJan 1933-May 1934 (Reel 4)
      - State Affiliated Leagues (Reel 4)
    - May - Dec 1935 (Reel 4)
      - Dr. Eric Matsner, Medical Director, ABCL (Reel 4)
      - Immunization and birth control, experiments with hormones reported (Reel 4)
      - Regional conference, St. LouisDec 1935 (Reel 4)
      - Controversy resulting from mass meetingDec 1935 (Reel 4)
      - Cardinal Hayes anti-birth control sermon and replies (Reel 4)
      - Responses to Cardinal Hayes by state (Reel 4)
    - 1935Mass meeting in Carnegie Hall (Reel 4)
    - 1935 (Reel 4, Folder 23)
      - 14th Annual convention, ChicagoJan 1935Dr. Henry Pratt Fairchild's appeal to advise "families of good stock" to have more children (Reel 4)
      - A.B.C.L. Family Planning Center, fund drive (Reel 4)
    - 1936 (Reel 5)
      - Birth control clinics (Reel 5)
      - Meetings and forums (Reel 5)
      - State leagues (Reel 5)
      - New England Regional ConferenceFeb 1936 (Reel 5)
      - U.S. appeals court permits importation of contraceptives by physicians (Reel 5)
    - 1937 (Reel 5)
      - General by states (Reel 5)
      - National Conference of Social Work, IndianapolisMay 1937 (Reel 5)
      - American Medical Association and birth control (Reel 5)
      - Hormonal birth control methods (Reel 5)
      - A.B.C.L. and support of Massachusetts birth control leaders (Reel 5)
    - 1938 (Reel 5)
      - General (Reel 5)
      - Euthanasia (Reel 5)
      - Regional Conference, Louisville, KYApr 1938 (Reel 5)
      - National Conference of Social Work, Seattle, WAJun 1938 (Reel 5)
      - Citizens Committee for Planned Parenthood (Reel 5)
    - Jan - Jun 1939 (Reel 5)
      - General (Reel 5)
      - San Francisco birth control exhibit at exposition controversy (Reel 5)
      - National Conference of Social Work, Buffalo, NYJun 1939 (Reel 5)
    - 1939-1940 (Reel 5)
      - Catholic opposition (Reel 5)
      - Southern Conference on Tomorrow's Children, Atlanta, GANovember 1939 (Reel 5)
      - General (Reel 5)
  - Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau 1930-37general and magazine articles (Reel 5)
  - Birth Control Federation of America (Reel 5)
    - 1940 (Reel 5)
    - 1939-1940Waterbury, CT, clinic raid, Jun 1939 (Reel 5)
    - 1940 (Reel 5)
      - Annual Meeting, New York CityJan 1940"Race Building in a Democracy" (Reel 5)
      - Gallup survey about birth control clinics (Reel 5)
    - 1941 (Reel 6)
      - Celebration of 25th anniversary of the opening of Margaret Sanger's Brooklyn clinic (Reel 6)
      - Cross country speeches of Mrs. Kathryn Trent, field director B.C.F.A. (Reel 6)
      - AbortionOct 1941 (Reel 6)
    - 1942Conference addressed by Julian Huxley and Pearl Buck (Reel 6)
  - Planned Parenthood Federation of America (Reel 6)
    - 1942 (Reel 6)
      - Negro Services of PPFA [includes speech by Baroness Ishimoto]Jan 1942 (Reel 6)
      - Progress book by states (Reel 6)
    - 1943 (Reel 7)
      - Morals of the WAAC's [Women's Army Auxiliary Corps] defended (Reel 7)
      - Abortion (Reel 7)
      - Annual meeting (Reel 7)
      - Negro Project (Reel 7)
    - 1944 (Reel 7)
      - Population (Reel 7)
      - Science and disease (Reel 7)
      - Abortion and adoption (Reel 7)
      - Personalities and miscellaneous statistics (Reel 7)
    - 1945-46 (Reel 7)
      - Publicity, "The Soldier Takes a Wife" (Reel 7)
      - 25th Anniversary Conference, New YorkJan 1946 "The Challenge of Tomorrow's Children" (Reel 7)
  - Margaret Sanger (Reel 7)
    - 1921 (Reel 7)
      - Town Hall Meeting13 Nov 1921 (Reel 7)
      - Arrests and trials (Reel 7)
    - 1952Bombay, India, and Japan (Reel 7)
    - 1919-1926 (Reel 7)
      - Lectures - USA (Reel 7)
      - Lectures - Japan (Reel 7)
    - 1935-36 (Reel 7)
      - Trip to India, Burma, Malay Straits, Penang, Singapore, Hong Kong, and Honolulu (Reel 7)
      - Addresses to All India Women's Conference (Reel 7)
    - 1955-56 (Reel 7)
      - General (Reel 7)
      - Speeches and reports (Reel 7)
      - Articles on the pill (Reel 7)
    - 1958-61 (Reel 7)
      - General (Reel 7)
      - Trip to India and Japan (Reel 7)